Frank Miles

1892 Lucretia Ave., Los Angeles, CA 900026 I 213-308-0469 I miles@barkingpixels.com
Web: http://www.barkingpixels.com I LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/frank-miles/14/562/42b/

Summary

I'm a user experience designer and front-end developer with a background in information technology (systems and network administration, and end-user support). I combine a user-centered design approach with strong technical chops. I've worked as the sole UX designer on various projects and am also a great collaborator.

Skill Set

Site maps, wireframes, user research, usability testing, personas, use cases, competitive analysis, card sorting, interaction design, information architecture, HTML, CSS, jQuery, prototyping, mobile design, responsive design

Previous Clients and Companies

Sony Entertainment Network; Science Inc.: Gumroad; Imagistic: Santa Barbara Botanic Garden; Petrol Advertising: Nexon, Turtle Beach; Marjorie Kaye UX Design, JLR Interactive, PCH Scuba

Employment History

January 2011 - present: Freelance User Experience Designer

- IA and UX design for Petrol Advertising doing IA, UX design and wireframing for Turtle Beach and Nexon Games.
- IA and UX design for a major electronics and media corporation, integrating marketing, transactional, and support elements site-wide as the sole UX designer, delivering a full UX deck and functional specifications.
- IA and UX redesign for Santa Barbara Botanic Garden's website.
- Subcontracting for Science Inc's UX lead for Gumroad, an online shopping site, from design to wireframes for merchant and consumer screens.
- Assisting senior UX designers (Marjorie Kaye UX Design, JLR Interactive) with wireframe production and annotations.

June 2006 - February 2013: Systems and Network Administrator Voice Media Group, LA Weekly, Culver City, CA

- IT infrastructure administration and support: LAN/WAN networking, servers (Windows, MacOS, Linux), desktops (Windows and MacOS), and mobile (iOS, Android).
- Sole server/network architect for configuration and deployment of Sophos enterprise
 antivirus and security software across a nationwide chain of weekly newspapers and their
 associated websites.
- Project lead on software evaluation and rollouts across a nationwide chain of 13 weekly newspapers and associated websites.
- End user support and training.

2002 - 2005: Student and Freelance IT Consultant

San Francisco, CA

Following the dot com collapse in the Bay Area, I took the opportunity to travel, and I later worked as an independent IT contractor for individuals and small businesses in San Francisco and attended the University of California at Berkeley as an undergraduate majoring in English literature.

2000 - 2002: Systems Administrator

respondTV, San Francisco, CA

respondTV was an interactive television startup. My responsibilities there included the following:

- Systems administration and end-user support and training.
- PBX administration and maintenance.
- Assets management and purchasing.

1998 - 2000: Systems Administrator

WellEngaged, Sausalito, CA

At this online community and conferencing software developer, I was responsible for the following:

- Systems administration and end-user support and training.
- PBX administration and maintenance.
- Assets management and purchasing.

1992 - 1998: Digital Prepress Manager and Technical Lead

Rapid, San Francisco, CA

- Managed a 7-person retouching, image assembly, and color separation team.
- Technical lead on Scitex workstations and imagesetters.
- Quality assurance.
- Training.

LinkedIn Recommendations

"You will not find a better professional or a more trusted colleague than Frank. His positive personality, can-do attitude, professional experience and natural leadership abilities make him the ideal team member in a large or small enterprise.

UX is a difficult area requiring a multitude of sensibilities and familiarity of diverse professions including an eye for artistic design and understanding as well as engineering and development capabilities, environment limitations and exploits, information architecture, platform rules and so many other intangibles. Frank brings a solid left-brain, right-brain experience set —both artistic and technical—that few UX professionals bring.

Frank is self-motivated, focused, productive and extremely detail oriented. He has a generosity of spirit and a remarkable personality that are key to his success as a team member and trusted colleague.

I highly recommend him both as a professional and as a person. Please feel free to discuss this with me in person."

Richard Cardran, Membership Committee, Interactive Media Peer Group at Academy of Television Arts & Sciences

"Miles was a stellar student in my Spring 2011 UX class. His semester project was well executed and demonstrated that he has real talent for the work. His wireframes were clean, professional-looking, and followed best practices. I anticipate seeing Miles churn out some great UX work for some very lucky employers."

Jaime Levy, User Experience Strategist & Designer

"One of my greatest accomplishments in life is that I was a part of the hiring process when we hired Miles at LA Weekly. Miles is in a VERY elite group known as "Favorite Employees I Have Worked With." He is incredibly smart and chock full of answers. There is no problem too big for him to tackle. Plus, he has one of the most finely tuned and acute senses of humor I have ever encountered. Any company that has Miles on their team should consider themselves lucky!"

Maureen Sullivan, SPHR, HR Director at Avanquest Software

"Frank is a top-notch, go-to guy with knowledge and patience to spare. Always prompt, respectful and resourceful, he is one of those can-do people you can always count on to get the job done and done right. He's also a blast as a human being. I look forward to the opportunity to work with him again."

Dean Purvis, Web Designer/Developer, Wordpress Guru, Web Content Creator, Writer/Editor

Education

- UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA User Experience Design
- University of California at Berkeley English Literature Major
- Liberty High School Bedford, VA

References

Available on request.